

Name: Robert Derek Norris

Date of Birth: 3. July 1970

Adress: Ortrudstraße 2, 12159, Berlin

Contact: +49 (0)151 655 18 876, robert.derek.norris@gmail.com

Online: https://wuntunsun.github.io/

Nationality: British and German

Languages: Native English, fluent written and spoken German

#### Profile

I'm an experienced software engineer, adept as both a facilitator and individual contributor having worked as manager and engineer in med-tech, the aeronautical industry, digital publishing and games. My strong technical knowledge encompasses many platforms and sectors. I enjoy a challenge, am open to change and am a continuous learner; an active listener who helps others articulate their thoughts, has an analytical mindset and am structured in resolving issues. I enable teams to bring their best work, mentoring those more junior than myself, and look to help team members bond.

#### Qualifications

Spiced Academy: November 2023-February 2024: Data Science Bootcamp

Subjects: NumPy, Pandas, Relational Databases + SQL, Machine Learning with Scikit-

learn, Supervised Learning: Classification + Regression, Non-linear models, Forecasting time series, Deep Learning with TensorFlow, Convolutional

Neural Networks.

Terra.do: August 2023-November 2023: Climate Change Bootcamp

Subjects: Foundational climate knowledge concepts, analytical skills for climate action,

systems thinking in geological, ecological, economic, and political dynamics across multiple scales, climate justice, collaboration, empathic engagement

and communication.

Coventry University: 1988–1992: BSc. Hons Computer Science 2i.

Subjects: Analytical Techniques, Statistics and Simulation, Computer-Architecture,

Software Engineering, Computer Graphics, Databases, Real-Time and

Embedded Computer Systems, Project Management.

Degree Dissertation: "The Interactive Manipulation of Bezier Curves and Surfaces"

# Skills Summary

#### Machine Learning

- Data Science with C++, Python, Pandas, NumPy and scikit-learn.
- GeoSpatial with rasterio, xdarray and GeoPandas.
- Data Visualisation using Vega-Lite, Plotly, Seaborn and Matplotlib.
- Programming in C++, Python, C#, Swift, PostgreSQL, Bash with Git, AWS and Docker.
- Linear Algebra, Analysis and Descriptive Statistics.

#### Programming and App Development

- Feature lead for health tracking, a major iOS vertical, utilising Swift and UIKit/SwiftUI.
- Responsible for the UML based software design for the Nintendo DS project Grundschule (released Jan. 2009), the complete C++ based development and its testing and quality assurance.
- Design and development work in C++ and C# to visualise 3D CAD models for the Aeronautical and Automobile industries.
- Design and development of Virtual Reality Software for, amongst other things, Virtual City visualisation using OpenGL on SGI Infinite Reality basis and OpenGL/DirectX based on Win32.
- Production of platform independent C++ code developed with MS Visual C++ using the Python script language for system configuration.
- Design and development of ESARAD, a UNIX (Sun/HP workstations) based thermal radiative analysis tool for the European Space Agency.

### Leadership

- Introduction of 'mobile first' strategy, including native mobile software development in a two-sided marketplace, stakeholder management, strategic guidance and oversight in the areas of analytics and Business Intelligence.
- Shaped the software process at an agency growing their digital business.
- Management, recruitment, technical conception, estimation and quality assurance for multiple Nintendo DS and iOS projects in cross-functional teams.
- Managerial and design responsibility for the Multimedia Playout Center project; a CORBA and Java Enterprise Beans based platform for interactive services in digital television (DVB) that were optimised using viewer profiling.

#### **Experience**

### March 2016 to August 2023: Senior Staff Software Engineer / Sharecare Inc.

- Introduction of Vega-Lite for data visualisation of tracker data.
- A 80% reduction in start time applying concurrency techniques.
- Successive improvements to the concurrency model for clarity and performance.
- Mentoring of junior and mid-level developers across all teams.
- Application of Domain Driven Design to the refinement of the tracking domain.
- » Motivation for change: A long time interest in combating climate change led me to take severance when offered which allows me to pivot into climate tech.

# May 2015 to October 2015: Product Lead Mobile / Helpling GmbH

- Release of an Android App to assist the daily work of cleaners. The tool initially addressed the areas of job and offer management, notifications, navigation and schedule optimisation.
- Strategic enhancement of the companies Analytics and Business Intelligence infrastructure to allow for the comparison of performance between web and app performance.
- Structured the Google Analytics reporting for mobile to all stakeholders.
- Established the infrastructure for native software development, including automated (both acceptance and unit testing) and continuous integration.
- » Motivation for change: A shift in investor emphasis from growth to profitability led Helpling GmbH to halt operation in four countries, making over 80 employees redundant including all those still in their 6 month probationary period.

## September 2010 to April 2015: Lead Developer / C3 Creative Code and Content

- Brought on board in the early stages of to grow their digital business. I participated in shaping the software process.
- Froschkönig (The Frog King) was awarded iPad Book-App of the Year by Apple in 2012.
- Introduced agile development to employees as part of a company wide talk on software development.
- Coached predominantly editorial designers in the production of digital assets for iOS.
- Performed reviews and established technologies for: Cross-platform development using Xamarin, and Continuous Integration using Bamboo.
- » Motivation for change: Aiming for a managerial role with functional and disciplinary responsibility, a shift in mobile development strategy, away from native platforms, led me to look elsewhere for my next career move.

# March 2010 to August 2010: IT Software Developer / PACE Aerospace Engineering and Information Technology GmbH

- C# development for an ,Aircraft Performance' Project. The project replaced the tedious calculation by hand of flight plans for an older aircraft used by the French Air Force.
- » Motivation for change: This was a project based contract at a previous employer (see below).

# August 2005 to March 2010: Freelance Development Director / syncRage GmbH (Secondary employment prior to September 2008)

- Development of a cut scene editor and player for TGE from GarageGames.
- Establishment of the companies agile software process, combining creative and development tasks. Coordination of external game designers and digital artists.
- Negotiating with publishers from the games industry.
- Handling submissions to Nintendo/Apple and liaising with them on issues pertaining to software reviews.
- » Motivation for change: The company failed during the development of Sponge Bob Jellyfish Jam.

# August 2001 to May 2008: IT Project Manager / PACE Aerospace Engineering and Information Technology GmbH

- Introduction of unit testing to the software process.
- Integration of the geometric modeller Open CASCADE with Open Inventor, and enhancements in OpenGL, as a framework that was expanded over the years to support many customer projects and the flagship product Engineering Workbench.
- » Motivation for change: The pursuit of a long standing wish to work in the games industry led me to progressively reduce my hours, and then change completely.

#### December 1997 to August 2001: Software Architect / artemedia AG

- Implementation of algorithms for Imposters, Occlusion-Culling, automatic Level of Detail and Dynamic Lighting.
- Multi threading architecture for multi screen based VR projections.
- » Motivation for change: Interest in progressing my career led to finding a new role as team leader.

## March 1995 to August 1997: Software Developer / European Gas Turbines

- A SET-ATS implementation for the exchange of product data.
- Research and presentation of STEP for the next generation of product data exchange.
- ESARAD software training for scientists at the German aeronautics and space institute DLR (Deutsches Zentrum für Luft und Raumfahrt) in Adlershof, Berlin.
- » Motivation for change: Moved to Germany for personal reasons.

### September 1992 to March 1995: System Manager / British Horse Society

- Assembly and supervision of a network with more than 100 PCs and a Novell v3.1 Server, 30 terminals and a SCO UNIX System.
- Automation of software updates across the network.
- » Motivation for change: The wish to take on a development role.